Guide to the Undergraduate Studies, Yale College, Records of the Dean
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Records of Martin Griffin as dean, 1973-1985, Accession 1989-A-038
  - Bladder Ball (see also: Box 5 folders 218-226), 1976-1977
    - Straw vote, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 125)
    - Zambre Yadunath visit, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 126)
  - Buckley Amendment & Privacy Protection Study
    - 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 127)
    - Final version-Yale Buckley Statement, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 129)
    - HEW Guidelines, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 130)
    - Material removed from files because of amendment, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 131)
    - Re: Student Records Privacy Protection Study, 1974-1976 (Box 3, Folder 132)
    - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 133)
    - Draft Recommendations, 1974-1977 (Box 3, Folder 134)
    - Statement of Yale University, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 135)
  - Shockley-Rusher Debate, 1974
    - Background, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 171)
    - Business, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 172)
    - Chairman's Statement, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 173)
    - Chronology, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 174)
    - Comments, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 175)
    - Correspondence, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 176 - 178)
    - Dean Horace Taft's letter to:
      - College Deans, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 179 - 180)
      - College Students, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 181)
    - University officials present at debate, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 182)
    - Interviews, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 184)
    - Magazine articles Executive Committee, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 185)
    - Minutes, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 186)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 187 - 188)
    - Notes from Executive Committee action, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 189)
    - Petitions for Readmission, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 190)
    - Petition of Students to the Executive Committee, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 191)
    - Posters, newspaper clippings, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 192)
    - Smith's Case Study, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 193)
    - Statement of Executive Committee, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 194)
    - Summary and Chronology, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 195)
    - we Were There, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 196)
    - Woodward Committee's Report, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 197)
    - Yale Corporation Reports, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 198)
    - Yale College Executive Committee Statement of Disruption of Debate, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 199)
  - Bladder Ball Material (See also: Box 3 Folders 101-126), 1976-1977
    - Briefs, 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 218)
    - Culler Committee Report, 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 219)
    - Executive Committee: Minutes ofMeeting, 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 220)
    - Key to names, 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 222)
    - Extra copies, 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 226)
  - Course of Study Committee, 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 227 - 245)
  - Leaves of Absence (Hansen's Essay), 1976-1977 (Box 6, Folder 246)
  - Grade Summaries, 1976-1977 (Box 6, Folder 247 - 269)
  - Athletics
    - Academic Speech to the Coaches, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 270)
    - A. I.A.W., 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 271)
    - Commencement: miscellany, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 272)
    - Course of Study Committee: Springterm, 1980-1981 (Box 6, Folder 273)
    - Eli International, Incorporated, 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 274)
    - Faculty Committee, 1980-1984 (Box 6, Folder 275 - 279)
    - Faculty Meeting, 1973-1974 (Box 6, Folder 280)
    - Griffin, Martin (Personal), 1973-1974 (Box 6, Folder 281)
    - Prize Committee, 1979-1980 (Box 6, Folder 282)
    - Student Affairs, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 283)
    - YCDO (Yale College Dean's Office) Annual Report, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 284)
  - Prizes
    - Bates Fellowship (Box 6, Folder 285)
    - Blum - Pelikan Report, 1973-1974 (Box 6, Folder 286)
    - Clare Fellowships, 1973-1974 (Box 6, Folder 287)
    - Committee on Honors and Academic Standing: Annual Report, Correspondence, Language Waivers, Membership &amp Master copies, 1981-1987 (Box 6, Folder 288 - 300)
    - Distinction in the Major
      - Awards, Letters, Registration Lists, Reports, 1981-1985 (Box 6, Folder 302 - 311)
      - Exceptional, 1983-1985 (Box 6, Folder 312 - 314)
      - Late Awards, 1982-1985 (Box 7, Folder 315 - 318)
  - Executive Committee: Degrees, Guidelines, Reports, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 319 - 336)
  - Freshman Counselor Program, 1973-1974 (Box 7, Folder 337)
  - Grading, 1973-1974 (Box 7, Folder 338)
  - High Stand: Candidates, Nominations, Prizes, 1981-1984 (Box 7, Folder 339 - 341)
  - Henry Fellowships, 1973-1974 (Box 7, Folder 342)
  - Snow, 1976-1984 (Box 7, Folder 350 - 353)
  - Minutes of the Dean's Meetings, 1975-1975 (Box 7, Folder 354)
  - Paul Mellon Center for British Art and British Studies, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 355)
  - General, 1973-1985 (Box 7, Folder 356 - 358)
  - Teaching, 1982-1984 (Box 7, Folder 361 - 362)
  - AFROTC (Air Force ROTC), 1983-1984 (Box 7, Folder 363)
  - Athletics and Yale College Dean's Office Annual Report, 1979-1985 (Box 8, Folder 364)
  - B.A./M.A, Combined: Actions, General, 1981-1985 (Box 8, Folder 365 - 371)
  - Burser's Letters, 1978-1980 (Box 8, Folder 372)
  - Certificates of Exclusion, 1979-1981 (Box 8, Folder 373)
  - Course Selection Period T&ampL Statement (including letter), 1983 (Box 8, Folder 374)
  - Directors of Undergraduate Studies, 1977-1985 (Box 8, Folder 375 - 385)
  - Distributional Requirements, Guidelines (Jubin Report), History, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 386 - 388)
  - Eli International, 1976-1980 (Box 8, Folder 389)
  - Film Committee, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 390)
  - Foreign Language Proficiency Committee, 1984-1985 (Box 8, Folder 391)
  - Freshman Counselors: Orientation Talk, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 392)
  - Kagan Committee Report, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 393)
  - Language Requirements: DUS Response, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 394)
  - Legal Studies: Proposal, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 395)
  - Liberal Arts 11, 1982-1983 (Box 8, Folder 396)
  - Library Rules, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 397)
  - New England ~ e a n ~Asssociation, 1973-19881 (Box 8, Folder 398)
  - Residential Colleges: A3G's Speech, 1982-1986 (Box 8, Folder 399)
  - Temporary Incompletes: Suttle Report, Fall and Spring terms, Statistics, 1974-1985 (Box 8, Folder 400 - 413)
  - Turner Committee Report, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 414)
  - YCDO (Yale College Dean's Office) and Dean's Assignments, 1982-1984 (Box 8, Folder 416 - 417)
  - Course of Study Chron file, 1978-1985 (Box 9, Folder 418 - 430)
  - Dean of Undergraduate Studies Chron file, 1974-1977 (Box 9, Folder 431 - 442)
  - Dean of Undergraduate Studies Chron file, 1977-1983 (Box 10, Folder 443 - 466)